"Episode 15"
《第15集》
underfoot
脚下
Madam Meng just sent the soup.
孟夫人刚刚送来了汤。
She said she made this soup herself.
她说这汤是她自己做的。
Did he do it himself?
是他自己做的吗？
It doesn't seem that way.
看来不是这样的。
It's all cool.
一切都很酷。
Take it away.
把它拿开。
Accept it.
接受。
Has anyone noticed that?
有人注意到了吗？
Your Majesty is not in the library.
陛下不在图书馆。
Teacher, don't worry. I sent them all back.
老师，别担心。 我把他们都送回来了。
let's go.
我们走吧。
chenzi
陈子
government
政府
Why do you look at me like that?
你为什么这样看着我？
You've been through a lot of hardships that seem to be in the past .
你经历了很多看似过去的困难。
What did I do when I was drunk yesterday ?
昨天我喝醉后做了什么 ？
You didn't do anything.
你什么也没做。
He just swore while riding the carriage. Just come back.
他只是在马车上骂了一句。 刚回来。
If the mistress is not drunk
如果主子没喝醉的话
You probably didn't know he was going through this pain.
你可能不知道他正在经历这种痛苦。
- Jong Ye-ran, you bastard - your mistress.
- 钟艺兰，你这个混蛋 - 你的情妇。
- Madam, stop - Master Rowe.
- 女士，停下来 - 罗少爷。
- You can't do this, sir . - I...
-你不能这么做，先生 。-我...
- I'm such an idiot - Madam, sir...
- 我真是个白痴 - 女士，先生......
someone in love with you
有人爱你
- Mistress - I hate you.
- 女主人 - 我恨你。
- Who do you think you are? - Mrs. Chao.
- 你以为你是谁？ - 赵女士。
- Do you still think I like you? - ma'am.
- 你还认为我喜欢你吗？ - 女士。
If you don't come back too late
如果你回来的太晚
I probably don't care about you.
我可能并不关心你。
Sir, ma'am, you are correct.
先生，女士，你们说得对。
You're right, don't pay attention to him.
你说得对，别理他。
You don't need to pay attention to him, ma'am.
女士，你不需要关注他。
- Are you - me or you?
- 你是 - 我还是你？
Let me tell you, yes, that's right.
我告诉你，是的，没错。
- Yes, it's me. - Yes, I feel bad.
- 是的，是我 - 是的，我感觉很糟糕
That's why I allowed you and Jong Ye-ran.
所以我才允许你和钟艺兰。
stay together
待在一起
- I... - Don't think I'm afraid of you.
- 我... - 别以为我害怕你。
- Yes, ma'am. - I'll tell you.
- 是的，女士 - 我会告诉你的
- Don't be afraid, sir - don't you dare command me.
- 别害怕，先生 - 你不敢命令我。
I know, I won't order you, Mistress.
我知道，我不会命令你，小姐。
I am trying to repent.
我正在努力悔改。
Otherwise I might kill you.
不然我可能会杀了你。
Madam, you are right.
女士，您说得对。
me...
我...
government
政府
- I... - Madam, you can't do this.
- 我... - 女士，你不能这样做。
government
政府
It's too dangerous.
太危险了。
I almost forgot to scold you.
我差点忘了骂你。
you are fat
你很胖
Yes, it's me.
是的，是我。
Please tell us.
请告诉我们。
My life is flourishing.
我的生活正在蓬勃发展。
So what are you doing?
那么你正在做什么？
force women to become concubines
强迫妇女为妾
Being such a helpless person
成为这样一个无助的人
You keep calling me that. “Nong Ying…” stayed all day.
你一直这么叫我。 “弄影……”呆了一整天。
I don't want to hear any more.
我不想再听了。
I will no longer call you “young lady ,” ma’am.
我不会再叫你“年轻女士 ”，女士。
I have warned you many times.
我已经警告过你很多次了。
But you're still out there causing trouble for me.
可你还是在外面给我添麻烦。
- Sir, I understand. - And you're right.
- 先生，我明白 - 你是对的
My brother wandered off and she did what she wanted.
我哥哥走开了，她做了她想做的事。
No matter what I said, no one listened to me.
不管我说什么，没有人听我的。
I'm listening, ma'am.
我在听，女士。
Who do you think you are?
你以为你是谁？
I'm listening to you.
我在听你说话。
Why should I endure these things?
我为什么要忍受这些事情？
- Madam, don't cry - I'm responsible for everything.
- 女士，别哭 - 我对一切负责。
Then he was hit by an arrow.
然后他就被箭射中了。
But everyone hates me anyway.
但无论如何，每个人都讨厌我。
That's not true. No one hates you.
这不是真的。没有人讨厌你。
Why is my life so difficult?
为什么我的生活如此艰难？
No one hates you, ma'am.
没有人讨厌你，女士。
- No one hates you - Why is my life so hard?
- 没有人恨你 - 为什么我的生活如此艰难？
Please sit down, ma'am, and don't cry.
女士，请坐下， 别哭。
Who did I curse?
我咒骂了谁？
Most of them are teachers. With Mr. Noi-Hwa
他们大多数是教师。 与内华先生
Then the Confessor and Butler Hua
然后是忏悔师 和华管家
And under your feet too.
也在你的脚下。
Has anyone else heard of this?
还有其他人听说过这个吗？
Madam, don't worry.
女士，别担心。
When Yama Hua took him to the carriage.
当阎花带着他上了马车时。
He started screaming.
他开始尖叫。
So only Yama Hua and I can hear you.
所以只有我和山华能听到你的声音。
Call Hua Rongzhou.
给华荣舟打电话。
You, mistress.
你，女主人。
government
政府
What happened to your face?
你的脸怎么了？
I accidentally got hurt.
我不小心受伤了。
Please ask during martial arts training.
请在武术训练时询问。
But here, no one can compete with you.
但在这里，没有人可以与你竞争。
What are you doing? Does it have to be difficult?
你在干什么？ 一定很困难吗？
Not at all.
一点也不。
Did I hurt you last night?
昨晚我伤害你了吗？
I didn't see you hit him while we were riding in the carriage .
我们坐马车的时候 我没看到你打他。
But I don't know what happened.
但我不知道发生了什么事。
When I went to get the carriage?
我什么时候去取马车？
Let me take a look. Please take off the bandage.
让我看看，请把绷带取下来。
I hurt myself.
我伤了我自己。
great
伟大的
You raised your voice to the point that it startled me.
你把声音提高到让我吃惊的程度。
Even if I'm drunk and can't control myself
即使喝醉了无法控制自己
I don't want to hurt anyone.
我不想伤害任何人。
too bright
太亮了
Madam, please don't poke me in the eye.
女士，请不要戳我的眼睛。
How soft is this?
这有多软？
No, sir, you didn't hit me.
不，先生，你没有打我。
Now let's go to Fahrenheit Mansion.
现在我们去飞轮海公馆吧。
Please prepare a carriage for me.
请为我准备一辆马车。
Madam, why all of a sudden?
小姐，怎么突然这样？
Are you coming back soon?
你很快回来吗？
I'm afraid that Mrs. Hua will do that...
就怕华夫人会这么做……
I have been avoiding this issue for a long time.
我长期以来一直回避这个问题。
Now is the time to face the truth.
现在是面对真相的时候了。
"Hua Family House"
《华家大宅》
Madam, please.
女士，请。
It's in the Now Butler Hua library.
现在华管家图书馆 里。
He asked me to welcome you.
他让我欢迎你。
And what about my mother?
那我妈妈呢？
Madam Hua is not feeling well.
华夫人身体不太舒服。
So she stayed home and rested.
于是她就待在家里休息。
I think he's still angry.
我想他还在生气。
During this time I didn't pay much attention to her.
这段时间我并没有太关注她。
it's crazy?
这很疯狂？
Your brother is still in prison.
你哥哥还在监狱里。
But do you still miss the Mu family?
但你还想念穆家吗？
You need to make the most of your time.
你需要充分利用你的时间。
Think about how to make your owner love you.
想想如何让你的主人爱你。
My master will never forgive me.
我的主人永远不会原谅我。
And I found a way
我找到了一种方法
I can't intervene in Shen'er's case.
沉儿的事我插手不了。
If my father wanted me to, I got out of prison.
如果我父亲愿意的话， 我就可以出狱。
You need to listen to me.
你需要听我说。
What can you do?
你能做什么？
last month
上个月
Have you tried several methods?
您尝试过几种方法吗？
And my brother is still in prison.
我的兄弟还在监狱里。
Father has another way.
父亲还有一个办法。
Besides, do you trust me or you?
再说了，你到底相信我还是你自己？
What changed you so much?
是什么让你发生了如此大的改变？
Who motivated you?
谁激励了你？
I'm just trying to atone for your sins.
我只是想弥补你的罪过
Father, I don't think you've ever killed anyone.
父亲，我认为您没有杀过人。
But do you know what you did wrong?
但你知道你做错了什么吗？
No, I should say the Hua family.
不，应该说华家。
How many mistakes have you made?
你犯了多少错误？
Where can merchants have clean hands?
商家哪里可以清白呢？
I didn't know you were so naive. Since when?
我不知道你这么天真。 从何时起？
I think you are just being diligent and kind.
我认为你只是勤奋和善良。
Can I get promoted like this?
我这样能升职吗？
it's me.
这就是我。
That's hard work
那是辛苦的工作
Climb the ranks to become a butler
晋升成为管家
So you came to argue with me.
所以你才来跟我争论。
You can stay here.
你可以留在这里。
When talking about justice
当谈论正义时
Don't forget your last name.
不要忘记你的姓氏。
Of course, I will never forget you.
当然，我永远不会忘记你。
Because my last name is Hua.
因为我姓华。
and you are my father
你是我的父亲
So I didn't turn my back.
所以我没有回头。
To the Fahrenheit family
致华氏家族
Father, will you listen to me or believe me?
父亲，您愿意听我的话还是相信我？
That's not important.
那不重要。
I will use my means to inform the Father.
我会用我的方式去通知天父。
wealth and honor
财富和荣誉
what you wanted in the past
你过去想要什么
It shows that you have reached a high standard.
这表明你已经达到了很高的标准。
Anyway, you are an idiot.
无论如何，你就是个白痴。
owner...
所有者...
Do you want to hit me again?
你还想再打我吗？
But this time I won't give up.
但这一次我不会放弃。
Again like before
又像以前一样
Now I'm the only one
现在我是唯一一个
My father will rely on me and guide me. My older brother is out of prison.
我的父亲会依靠我、引导我。 我的哥哥已经出狱了。
When can I help my brother?
我什么时候可以帮助我的兄弟？
Dad needs to calm down.
爸爸需要冷静下来。
Then come to me and find out.
然后来找我了解一下。
When will your brother be released from prison?
你弟弟什么时候能出狱？
Father, don't forget. what i just said
父亲，别忘了。 我刚才说的话
How long will my brother be in prison?
我弟弟要在监狱里待多久？
It depends on it. How quickly do you plan to act?
这取决于它。 您计划多快采取行动？
Madam, are you going or not?
小姐，你去还是不去？
Butler Hua gave me an order. Please prepare lunch.
华管家给我下了命令。 请准备午餐。
I still have work to do, so it would be better not to eat.
我还有工作要做，还是不吃饭比较好。
Madam, why don’t you go see Madam Hua?
夫人， 您怎么不去看看华夫人呢？
During this time she was unable to eat or sleep.
在此期间，她无法进食或睡觉。
And I lost a lot of weight.
我体重减轻了很多。
- No, - Qian'er.
- 不， - 倩儿。
How long does it take to get home?
需要多长时间才能到家？
Why are you in such a hurry to go back?
你为什么这么急着回去？
I have a lot of work to do.
我有很多工作要做。
We have to hurry.
我们得快点。
Otherwise, I'm afraid Mom will think I'm not doing anything.
不然我怕 妈妈会觉得我什么都没做。
For those things, wait a little longer. No damage.
对于这些事情，再等等吧。 无损伤。
I heard you're back.
我听说你回来了。
So, we prepared some of your favorite snacks.
所以，我们准备了一些您最喜欢的小吃。
Please stay with me for a moment.
请陪我一会儿。
no.
不。
Come on, come on.
好啦好啦。
I have something to say, so please go.
我有话要说，所以请你走吧。
this
这
Have some.
有一些。
I made your favorite dessert.
我做了你最喜欢的甜点。
You haven't been home for a while.
你有一段时间没回家了。
Let's try it and see. Is the taste still the same?
让我们尝试一下看看。 味道还是一样吗？
This is delicious.
这个好吃。
Your younger brother likes it too.
你弟弟也喜欢。
I remember making dessert.
我记得做甜点。
And he'll be watching from my side
他会在我身边看着
Once completed, he will quickly bring it to you.
完成后， 他会很快给你带来。
And he ate the rest.
然后他把剩下的都吃了。
Only after eating my fill
只有在吃饱之后
like i said before
就像我之前说的
I'll take care of your business myself.
你的事我自己来处理。
Mom, you don't have to tell me.
妈妈，你不必告诉我。
With such beautiful words
用如此美丽的话语
i know
我知道
you probably think
你可能认为
Am I biased against your sister?
我对你妹妹有偏见吗？
Anyway, he is. my only son
无论如何，他是。 我唯一的儿子
You haven't had a son yet.
你还没有儿子。
So I don't know.
所以我不知道。
How important is your son?
你的儿子有多重要？
“How could you not know?”
“你怎么会不知道？”
“It was like this in my past life.”
“我的前世也是这样。”
“He’s not interested in me at all.”
“他对我根本不感兴趣。”
“I only care about my son.”
“我只关心我的儿子。”
when you were young
你小时候
I rarely take you to my old house.
我很少带你去我的老房子。
to meet grandpa
去见爷爷
I think
我认为
You know what I'm thinking.
你知道我在想什么。
Are you my grandfather or not?
你到底是不是我爷爷？
You are still very young.
你还很年轻。
When Grandma Died
奶奶去世时
Surely you remember them.
你肯定还记得他们。
You can't.
你不能。
What happened to grandma?
奶奶怎么了？
I never said you.
我从来没有说过你。
You are now someone's wife.
你现在是某人的妻子了。
It's time to talk about it.
是时候谈谈它了。
your grandmother
你的祖母
Be a proper wife According to your grandfather's laws
按照你祖父的法律，做一个合格的妻子
Let me be a legitimate child even though I am called to do so.
让我成为一个合法的孩子，即使我被要求这样做。
I also did not receive treatment.
我也没有接受治疗。
concubine's son
妾的儿子
Do you know why?
你知道为什么吗？
Because of your grandmother
因为你的祖母
gave birth to me a daughter
为我生了一个女儿
my daughter
我的女儿
today is your birthday
今天是你的生日
What do you want? as a birthday present
你想要什么？ 作为生日礼物
I don't want anything from you.
我不想从你那里得到任何东西。
I just wish my dad would play with me all day.
我只希望爸爸能陪我玩一整天。
Okay, what should we play?
好吧，我们应该玩什么？
Let's agree.
我们同意吧。
Master, the young master coughed non-stop.
少爷，少爷咳个不停。
Pastor Jang, please.
有请张牧师。
Go and check out the symptoms.
去检查一下症状。
If he's sick, go to the doctor.
如果他生病了，就去看医生。
Sir, you don't know anything about medicine.
先生，您对医学一无所知。
You can't say that.
你不能这么说。
I will go and take a look.
我去看看。
Father, you just promised me.
爸爸，你刚刚答应过我。
He said he would play with me all day
他说他会陪我玩一整天
Now you are broken.
现在你已经破碎了。
Your little brother is sick.
你的弟弟病了。
But I still want to play again
但我还是想再玩一次
I will go and take a look.
我去看看。
He's doing well. I'll come again.
他做得很好。我会再来的。
- Father - Elder
- 父亲 - 长老
- mother's son - father
- 母亲的儿子 - 父亲
to let go...
放手...
Your master has given you this. It's a birthday present.
这是你的主人给你的。 这是一份生日礼物。
What do you have in your hands?
你手里有什么？
A jade bracelet given to me by my father.
父亲送给我的玉镯。
I want that too.
我也想要那个。
You are a boy. What are you going to do with it?
你是一个男孩。 你打算用它做什么？
I don't care.
我不在乎。
I want everything you have.
我想要你拥有的一切。
What makes you think? You can take my things.
是什么让你这么想？ 你可以拿走我的东西。
I want to teach you a lesson.
我想给你一个教训。
Instead of mom?
代替妈妈？
Let's see, I am your father's son.
让我看看，我是你父亲的儿子。
You are just a daughter.
你只是一个女儿。
You have to get married sooner or later.
你迟早得结婚。
at that time
当时
The whole house will be mine.
整个房子都将是我的了。
If you dare to hit me
如果你敢打我
I will banish your mother and make her a beggar.
我会放逐你的母亲，让她成为乞丐。
Mr. Noi Chao
内超先生
Madam, your daughter is the eldest.
夫人，您的女儿是长女。
How could she do this to her brother?
她怎么可以这样对她弟弟？
So how?
又怎样？
I will teach the queen's sons, daughters and wives.
我会教导女王的儿子、 女儿和妻子。
This is normal.
这个是正常的。
I know you can't have a son.
我知道你不能有儿子。
So you don't like my son.
所以你不喜欢我儿子。
But even though my son is the son of a concubine
但尽管我的儿子是妾的儿子
He is also the heir. In the future of Mr.
他也是继承人。 在先生的未来里
If the person is seriously injured
如果此人受重伤
The master's family line ends here.
主人的家谱到此结束。
- There it is - that's enough.
- 就在那里 - 够了。
Why all the fuss?
为什么这么大惊小怪？
you...
你...
I'm sorry about your brother.
我对你弟弟的事感到抱歉。
sibling
兄弟
After all, harming others is always wrong.
毕竟，伤害别人总是不对的。
Besides, you are his sister.
更何况你还是他的妹妹。
I need to apologize.
我需要道歉。
your younger brother
你弟弟
Sir, I will yield to him.
先生，我会屈服于他。
And from now on I don't want anything else.
从现在开始 我什么都不想要了。
owner...
所有者...
Your grandfather has never been violent towards me.
你的祖父 从来没有对我使用过暴力。
But every time we argue
但每次我们吵架的时候
with my younger brother
和我弟弟
He will always be biased in favor of his son.
他永远都会偏向于他的儿子。
he felt it
他感觉到了
Sooner or later his daughter will have to get married.
他的女儿迟早 要结婚。
And someone else's
还有别人的
your grandmother can't have a son
你的祖母 不能有儿子
And she had to suffer all her life.
而她一生都必须受苦。
I don't want to live like that anymore.
我不想再这样生活了。
And I don't want you to suffer like me.
我也不希望你 像我一样受苦。
Who looks like your father? Giving all my heart and soul
谁长得像你父亲？ 付出我全部的心和灵魂
to the factory
到工厂
And I don't plan on having a concubine.
而且我也不打算纳妾。
Because I gave birth.
因为我生了。
Your older brother is your first child.
你的哥哥是你的第一个孩子。
Like if I give birth to a daughter, you'll be alone.
就像如果我生了一个女儿， 你就会孤身一人。
At the Hua Family Mansion
华家大宅内
There must have been many concubines.
一定有很多妾。
Mom, you said you had to work hard.
妈妈，您说过要努力工作。
Because of prejudice
因为偏见
Then why did you become a human?
那你为什么会变成人类呢？
Who is also prejudiced against sons?
谁还对儿子有偏见？
Qian'er, it's not the same.
倩儿，不一样啊。
Shen'er is your real brother.
沉儿是你亲弟弟。
He will protect you.
他会保护你。
Because you are of the same blood
因为你们有 同样的血脉
Without my brother
没有我的兄弟
What do you think life at the head residence is like?
您认为总居的生活是什么样的？
Would it be this easy?
会有这么容易吗？
Your father is going to marry another woman.
你父亲要娶另一个女人。
whenever
每当
And I could only watch helplessly
而我只能眼睁睁地看着
If the father had another son
如果父亲还有一个儿子
You need to pay attention to him. more than usual
你需要注意他。 比平时更多
Without the support of the Fahrenheit family,
如果没有飞轮海家族的支持，
Your owner may have treated you badly.
你的主人可能对你不好。
And you will suffer in silence.
而你将默默承受痛苦。
At the head residence
在头部住处
For this reason I have hastened for you.
为此我才急忙去找你。
Have a son as soon as possible.
尽快生个儿子吧。
Even if my father ignores me
即使父亲不理我
Your position is unwavering.
你的立场是坚定不移的。
And you have a brother.
而且你有一个兄弟。
No matter how stupid that person is
不管那个人有多么愚蠢
He is the only One we can rely on.
他是我们唯一可以依靠的一位。
Did you understand?
你明白了吗？
That's it.
就是这样。
My mother has never lived. The same goes for life and death situations.
我妈妈从来没有住过。 对于生与死的情况也是如此。
No wonder you say this.
难怪你会这么说。
stupid kid
愚蠢的孩子
Do you understand what I'm saying?
你明白我所说的吗？
What does it say about life and death?
关于生与死，它说了什么？
There is nothing.
没有什么。
i just want to say
我只想说
I will help my brother get out of prison.
我会帮助我的兄弟出狱。
So mom, don't worry.
所以妈妈别担心。
great.
伟大的。
good
好的
Now, try some.
现在，尝试一些。
Eat again.
再吃吧。
How long does it take to get home?
需要多长时间才能到家？
I salute you
我向你们致敬
Sir, you have eaten the soup.
先生，您已经把汤喝完了。
Was it the night before I sent it or not?
是我寄出的前一天晚上 吗？
Song An brought it to me.
宋安拿来给我的。
The taste is pretty good.
味道还不错。
I'm glad to hear that news.
我很高兴听到这个消息。
I feel anxious if I add too much sugar.
如果我加太多糖，我会感到焦虑。
You might think it's too sweet.
你可能会觉得太甜了。
It's kind of sweet. But there's still enough to eat.
有点甜。但吃的还是够的。
This 2 nights and 3 days
这三天两夜
Your second uncle works at Hwangcheong .
你二叔在黄清工作 。
It's nice to be in one place.
呆在一个地方真好。
My mother hasn't returned yet.
我妈妈还没有回来。
if you have time
如果你有时间
Then go see your uncle.
那你就去找你舅舅吧。
To my uncle
给我叔叔
He's going to be my father's younger brother.
他将成为我父亲的弟弟。
But we are not close to each other.
但我们彼此并不亲近。
I don't want to disturb him.
我不想打扰他。
Bad people have a side. That's also unfortunate.
坏人也有好的一面。 这也是不幸的。
Mistress, this is all money.
老婆，这都是钱啊。
It has been withdrawn from the factory.
已从工厂撤回。
This is enough.
这就够了。
- Qianzi - Lord, madam.
- 千子 - 先生，夫人。
Take this and keep it.
拿着这个并保留它。
You, mistress.
你，女主人。
Madam, what are you going to do with all that money?
女士， 你打算用这些钱做什么？
Just use it for important purposes.
只是将其用于重要目的。
chenzi
陈子
Have you ever wanted to be free?
你曾经想过自由吗？
And left the head family residence.
并离开了族长府邸。
Should I go and live my own life?
我应该去过自己的生活吗？
Madam, what does that mean?
女士， 这是什么意思？
Becoming a servant I'm wasting my time here every day
成为仆人 我每天都在这里浪费时间
Not a good idea at all.
根本不是一个好主意。
Madam, are you going to kick me out?
小姐，你要把我赶出去吗？
What did I do wrong?
我做错了什么？
No, I'm not after you, I...
不，我不是在追你，我……
Never mind. Stop talking about this.
没关系。别再说这个了。
You are such a crybaby.
你真是个爱哭鬼。
How can I live life without you?
没有你我该如何生活？
If you kick me out, I'll die.
如果你把我赶出去，我就会死。
Don't act like a crybaby. Same as Qianzi.
别表现得像个爱哭鬼。 与千子同。
And don't forget to see your doctor.
并且不要忘记去看医生。
Please give me some good medicine.
请给我一些好药。
Please come and treat the wound on my face.
请过来帮我处理一下脸上的伤口。
Don't just use a bandage.
不要只使用绷带。
Leave no scars.
不留疤痕。
On a handsome face
俊美的脸上
Please ask me first.
请先问我。
One person is a crybaby.
有一个人是个爱哭鬼。
The other person feels embarrassed.
对方感到羞耻。
Why are people around me so sensitive?
为什么我身边的人都这么敏感？
Sir, we have recorded the damage.
先生，我们已经记录了损坏情况。
From the Lee family
来自李氏家族
All people born into the Zhang family were eliminated
张家出生的人全部被淘汰
And calculate the amount
并计算金额
All outstanding balances have been paid.
所有未清余额均已支付。
We warned them several times.
我们多次警告他们。
However, Jang's family still refused to pay.
但张某的家人仍拒绝付款。
teacher
老师
Teacher, please.
老师，请。
What problem did Young Master Ho have this time?
何少爷这次遇到什么问题了？
He said while crying.
他一边哭一边说道。
He was bitten by a rat.
他被老鼠咬了。
You can get sick and die in prison.
你可能会在监狱里生病甚至死亡。
when he was bitten
当他被咬的时候
Take him to a doctor and check him out.
带他去看医生并检查一下。
We took him but he wouldn't let the doctor.
我们带了他，但他不让医生带我们去。
Please touch him.
请触摸他。
He said he was afraid he might be poisoned.
他说他担心自己可能会中毒。
great.
伟大的。
When he still had the strength to cry
当他还有力气哭的时候
It has been proven that there is nothing serious.
已经证明没有什么严重的事情了。
Please make sure you eat three meals a day regularly.
请确保一日三餐有规律。
And you don't need to pay attention to him.
而且你不需要关注他。
Teacher, please...
老师，请...
He was locked up for a month.
他被关了一个月。
When will the investigation begin?
调查什么时候开始？
last month
上个月
All the guards were very tired.
所有的守卫都非常疲惫。
Please, because of him.
拜托，因为他。
you think i can
你认为我可以
Is it okay to interrogate me at any time?
可以随时审问我吗？
First, wait for the warrant.
首先，等待搜查令。
You don't need to ask any more.
你不需要再问了。
If nothing happens, you can leave.
如果没什么事的话，你就可以离开了。
Accept it.
接受。
Be sure to come and get it.
一定要来拿。
"Middle-aged Mansion"
《中年宅邸》
Confessor Mu, would you like to read it tomorrow?
穆忏悔， 你明天想念吗？
Be careful as it may hurt your eyes.
请小心，因为它可能会伤害您的眼睛。
Anyway, I can't sleep.
反正我睡不着。
It's also good to read a book for a while.
读一会儿书也不错。
It's been almost a month now.
现在已经快一个月了。
A brave villain who harmed you.
一个伤害你的勇敢的恶棍。
He is still imprisoned without any interrogation.
他仍然被关押在监狱里，没有受到任何审讯。
And the owner did nothing.
而主人却什么也没做。
I watched Mistress today. Go outside again.
今天看了《女主》 再出去吧。
She didn't seem fazed.
她看上去并不慌张。
She went out to buy things.
她出去买东西了。
And when I visited my parents nothing seemed to have happened.
当我拜访父母时， 似乎什么也没发生。
This issue is not about her.
这个问题与她无关。
She wouldn't have felt anything.
她不会有任何感觉。
But that villain, I am her brother.
但那个恶棍， 我是她的兄弟。
He was so scared that he ran away.
他非常害怕，于是逃跑了。
But the owner did not come to comfort him.
但主人并没有过来安慰他。
Besides, he lets his mistress do whatever she wants.
而且，他还让他的情妇为所欲为。
He is prejudiced against her. There are already too many.
他对她有偏见。 已经太多了。
Continue like this
继续这样
If you suddenly lose hope
如果你突然失去希望
Let the criminals go.
让罪犯走吧。
That's not surprising at all.
这一点也不奇怪。
Please go and get me some water.
请去给我拿点水来。
I want to shower and sleep.
我想洗澡然后睡觉。
One of the servants, the mistress housekeeper Hua, sent this.
这是其中一名下人， 华管家大小姐送来的。
Your father may be stubborn.
你的父亲可能很固执。
And refuse to hear the truth
并拒绝听到真相
But there are enough problems. only son
但问题已经够多了。 独子
He acted really quickly.
他的动作确实很快。
Madam, who are these people?
夫人， 这些人是谁？
Call Hua Rongzhou.
给华荣舟打电话。
You, mistress.
你，女主人。
I need help. This task is complicated.
我需要帮助。 这项任务很复杂。
And there's no one I can trust.
而且没有人是我可以信任的。
It's nearby.
就在附近。
Can you help me with this errand?
你能帮我做这个差事吗？
I already have it, sir.
我已经有了，先生。
I am willing to die for you.
我愿意为你去死。
It's not that serious, just wake up.
没那么严重， 醒醒吧。
Here is a list
这是一个列表
And I have enough money
而且我有足够的钱
Collect their debts. All within 3 days.
追收他们的债务。 全部在3天内完成。
I asked for a hostess.
我要求找一位女主人。
Our Little Sentry I am now an adult.
我们的小哨兵 我现在已经是一个成年人了。
He can handle important matters on his own.
他可以自己处理重要的事情。
That person is there.
那个人就在那里。
"빚"
“빚”
Well done
做得好
I think I underestimated you.
我想我低估了你。
Now just one day has passed.
现在仅仅一天过去了。
Job done.
任务完成。
Go and call Qianzi.
去给千子打电话。
I'll handle it.
我会处理的。
early in the morning
清晨
Please, mistress.
拜托了，女主人。
government
政府
Why handwriting?
为什么要手写？
It seems different from before.
似乎和以前不一样了。
My right hand is injured.
我的右手受伤了。
So it affects your handwriting.
所以它会影响你的笔迹。
A woman's hands are very precious.
女人的手是非常珍贵的。
Even if the owner gets angry
就算主人生气了
He couldn't do that to you.
他不能那样对你。
Madam, you were an expert. Gogeumnori, Gogeumnori
女士，您是一位专家。 后金诺里，后金诺里
calligraphy and painting
书画
But now he's ruined everything.
但现在他毁了一切。
Thanks to that, please take this and give it to Zong Yeran.
拜托， 请你收下这个，交给宗野然吧。
“Divorce certificate”
《离婚证明》
Madam, this...
夫人，这……
What about divorce papers?
离婚证怎么办？
I have other business to attend to. hurry up, please.
我还有别的事要处理。请快点。
Madame Chao
赵女士
this is...
这是...
Mr. Mu’s wife said this.
穆先生的妻子这样说道。
She was in a bad mood. And he won't let anyone see him.
她心情不好。 而且他不会让任何人看到他。
Do you have light body skills?
你有光身技能吗？
I have it.
我有。
take me beyond the wall
带我越过墙
Stop bragging and hurry.
别再吹牛了，快点吧。
What should we do?
我们应该做什么？
You have to hold me in your arms or ride me on your back.
你必须把我抱在怀里或者骑在你的背上。
Hurry up.
赶快。
Hurry up!
赶快！
Madam, I'm sorry.
女士，对不起。
How did you get here?
你是怎么来到这里？
Non-penitents do not accept guests.
不悔改的人不接待客人。
I can't go in.
我不能进去。
Mu's concubine
穆氏小妾
let's go.
我们走吧。
Yamhwa, it's you...
雅华，是你……
What do you want?
你想要什么？
I want to talk to you. But they wouldn't let me in.
我想跟你说话。 但他们不让我进去。
So I had to find another entrance.
所以我不得不寻找另一个入口。
I have nothing to talk to you about.
我没什么可跟你谈的。
Read this first and then speak.
请先阅读此内容，然后再说话。
What does it mean?
这是什么意思？
Are you threatening me?
你在威胁我吗？
No, I'm here to make a deal.
不，我来这里是为了做一笔交易。
agreement or
协议或
With the debt of all servants
带着所有仆人的债务
Among the Mu family?
穆家之中？
Please send Hwasen.
请发送华森。
Then I will pay off all my debt.
然后我会还清所有的债务。
The servant of the former Mu family gives you
以前穆家的仆人给你
And if I don’t want to, just send Hua Shen away.
如果我不愿意， 就把华神打发走吧。
What will you do?
你会怎么做？
I'm not here to threaten you.
我不是来威胁你的。
So I won't accept it. the life of your species
所以我不会接受。 你的物种的生命
Come as a negotiation tool
作为谈判工具
Didn't you come here to threaten me?
你不是来威胁我的吗？
So what does this mean?
那么这是什么意思？
This is a warning.
这是一个警告。
You can find debt products.
您可以找到债务产品。
Easily for your entire species
轻松适合您的整个物种
This proves that I can do more.
这证明我可以做得更多。
whether you believe it or not
不管你信不信
If it's a matter of negotiation
如果是谈判问题
I have more cards than you.
我的卡比你多。
Mistakes made by Hwasen
华森犯下的错误
I am not against it.
我并不反对。
He will pay a huge price.
他将付出巨大的代价。
But because of what he didn't do
但因为他没有做的事
I won't allow you. He also made false accusations.
我不会允许你的。 他还提出了不实指控。
Each person's opinion on right and wrong
每个人对对与错的看法
to be different
与众不同
Will commit a serious crime against the Hua family
将对华家 犯下重罪
We don't have to pay for it.
我们不必为此付费。
For what we didn't do
对于我们没有做的事情
Therefore, Muyao
所以，慕瑶
Because I want revenge
因为我要报仇
And turn the case around
并扭转案情
Come and be honest.
来吧，说实话。
I won't interfere. your quest for truth
我不会干涉。 你对真理的追求
But if you keep using dirty methods
但如果你继续使用肮脏的方法
I won't pretend I didn't see it.
我不会假装我没有看到它。
People who wanted to punish Huashen
想要惩罚华神的人
This is Yeongju.
这里是荣州。
What do you think you will get if you come to me?
你认为如果你来找我你会得到什么？
Mu Yao
穆瑶
Don't belittle your condition.
不要小看你的条件。
In Jong Ye-ran’s mind.
在钟艺兰的心里。
And do you think Zhong Yeran doesn’t know?
而且你以为钟也然不知道吗？
This time we set the scene.
这次我们布置了场景。
People in love are really stupid.
恋爱中的人真的很傻。
last month
上个月
Zhong Ye Lan did not give any orders.
钟夜兰没有下达任何命令。
punish my brother
惩罚我的兄弟
And just lock it up
然后把它锁起来
What do you think is the reason?
您认为原因是什么？
He was angry that day.
那天他很生气。
Until I almost killed my brother.
直到我差点杀了我的兄弟。
Don't lie to me.
别对我撒谎。
Deep down, you know.
内心深处，你知道。
Am I telling the truth or not?
我说的是真话还是假话？
Besides, Zhong Ye Lan understands you.
况且，钟夜兰也理解你。
more than I
比我多
Although anger plays a role
虽然愤怒也有一定的作用
With his decision in the first place
他首先做出的决定
He noticed something suspicious.
他注意到了一些可疑的事情。
Later when it calms down
后来当平静下来的时候
No matter how ridiculous Hua Shen is
不管华神有多么可笑
He probably wouldn't dare come and cause chaos.
他大概不敢过来闹事。
At Lee's wedding
在李的婚礼上
You can't even fool me.
你连我都骗不了。
What makes you think you can fool him?
是什么让你觉得你可以愚弄他？
Why do you think so? I know him better than I know myself.
你为什么这么认为？ 我比我自己更了解他。
It's not that I know him better.
这并不是说我更了解他。
It's just Jong-ye.
这只是钟业。
Accidentally exposing one's own sins
一不小心暴露了自己的罪孽
In front of me a few days ago
前几天在我面前
You don't want to listen to me.
你不想听我的。
And I don't want it now. I would say the same thing.
而我现在不想要它。 我也会说同样的话。
My heart aches.
我心疼。
I'm not in the mood to argue with you.
我没心情和你争论。
Don't mess with me.
别惹我。
Hua Chen...
华晨...
Doing so will put your mind at ease.
这样做会让你心里踏实。
If you want to kill my brother, please.
如果你想杀我的兄弟，就请吧。
You take advantage of the fact that:
您可以利用以下事实：
Zhong Yueran likes you.
钟悦然喜欢你。
And think of a plan
并想出一个计划
It's full of loopholes.
它充满了漏洞。
If I hadn't stopped him that day
如果那天我没有阻止他
He would have killed my brother.
他会杀了我的兄弟。
With his sword gone
随着他的剑消失
And you will have avenged Linglong.
你也将为玲珑报仇。
Huaqian
华谦
I never dreamed I would see this side of you.
我做梦也没想到我会看到你的这一面。
But I want to remind you.
但 我想提醒你。
The most fragile thing in the world
世界上最脆弱的东西
It's humanity
这就是人性
soon
很快
Your goodness will overcome.
你的善良将会战胜。
Because of what happened in the past
因为过去发生的事情
I'll allow it this time.
这次我会允许的。
But if you use this dirty method
但如果你使用这种肮脏的方法
Against the Hua family again
再次与华家作对
I will never show you mercy again.
我再也不会对你仁慈了。
Debt securities brought in today
今天引入的债务证券
Consider this a warning.
将此视为警告。
Hua Qian, what exactly do you want?
华谦，你到底想要什么？
teach your nature
教导你的本性
Are you angry?
你在生气吗？
then
然后
Think carefully before doing anything.
做任何事情之前都要仔细考虑。
if you did something wrong
如果你做错了什么
You will be caught.
你会被抓住的。
one more
多一个
I already confessed to Jong Ye-ran.
我已经向钟艺兰表白了。
I disguised myself as you
我把自己伪装成你
I sent Zhong Yue Lan back to you.
我把钟月兰还给你了。
I don't owe you anything anymore.
我不再欠你什么了。
Give it back to me?
把它还给我？
Qianzi should have taken the divorce papers.
千子应该把离婚证拿走。
I went to give it to Zhong Ye Lan.
我去给钟夜兰了。
From now on, your inner self and emotions
从现在开始，你的内心 和情感
You can handle it yourself.
你可以自己处理。
I will never get involved again.
我永远不会再参与其中。
Do you want a divorce?
你想离婚吗？
yes
是的
Don't get me involved.
别让我参与其中。
And it's a matter between you and Zhong Ye-ran.
而且这是你和钟业然之间的事情。
Madame Chao
赵女士
Where have you been?
你去哪儿了？
Go and sort out your old problems.
去解决你的老问题吧。
What are you doing here?
你在这里做什么？
Qianzi explained. Did I not hear you clearly?
千子解释道。 我没听清楚吗？
What does it mean?
这是什么意思？
When leaving the head family residence
离开本族住所时
Everyone will be happy.
每个人都会幸福。
That's nice, right?
这很好，对吧？
I thought you were going back to the painter's mansion.
我还以为你要回画家宅邸呢
Is that okay?
可以吗？
What does it mean?
这是什么意思？
Smiling Hua couldn't even protect himself.
笑华连自己都保护不了。
You are just a woman.
你只是一个女人。
The Hwa family will protect you. How long can I receive it?
华家人会保护你。 多久可以收到？
Teacher, what does this mean?
老师，这是什么意思？
Are you not going to say anything?
你不打算说什么吗？
So let me guess.
那么让我猜一下。
What you mean is
你的意思是
You will help Mu Yao reverse his decision.
你将帮助穆瑶扭转他的决定。
Because I feel sorry for you
因为我为你感到难过
So he allowed me to stay at the head house.
于是他就让我住在主屋。
I won't get involved.
我不会参与其中。
With the fall of the Fahrenheit family
随着飞轮海家族的没落
then
然后
Sir, you don't have to worry at all.
先生，您完全不用担心。
You saved my life.
你救了我的命。
I can't ignore you.
我不能忽视你。
So even if you want to go
所以即使你想去
Just wait a little longer.
再等一会儿。
I can protect you.
我可以保护你。
Only if you were still in the Zhong Family Mansion.
前提是你还在钟家府。
I accidentally saved your life.
我不小心救了你的命。
If we go back to that incident
如果我们回到那件事
I will definitely remain silent and do nothing.
我一定会保持沉默，什么也不做。
You don't have to take it to heart.
你不必把它放在心上。
Please think of me as a reward.
请把我当作奖励。
mistake made
犯了错误
You and I don't owe each other anything.
你我互不欠对方什么。
I don't need you.
我不需要你。
I can protect myself.
我可以保护自己。
Can you protect yourself?
你能保护自己吗？
how?
如何？
You will protect yourself.
你会保护自己。
Like I did by creating a slanderous scene ?
就像我制造诽谤场面一样？
Who will we do the scene with? What does this have to do with you?
我们将和谁一起拍摄这个场景？ 这和你有什么关系？
I am kind enough to ask for a divorce.
我好心提出离婚。
So that you and Mu Yao can be together.
这样你就可以和慕瑶在一起了。
Why should you be angry with me?
你为什么要生我的气？
Are you kind enough?
你够善良吗？
Not at all, Hua Qian.
一点也不，华谦。
You always think about yourself.
你总是为自己着想。
- I... - You said you liked me.
- 我... - 你说你喜欢我。
So he disguised himself as Mu Yao.
于是他乔装打扮成慕瑶。
Then you want to marry me.
那你想嫁给我。
So they poisoned me.
所以他们给我下了毒。
Even when you took the arrow for me
即使你为我拿走了箭
You are just looking for excuses.
你只是在寻找借口。
to absolve myself
为自己开脱
That's enough for now
现在就够了
You want a divorce.
你想离婚。
And left the head family residence.
并离开了族长府邸。
You went to see the princess.
你去见公主了。
So he ordered, Mu Yao, marry me.
于是他命令， 慕瑶，嫁给我。
And forced me to choose
并强迫我做出选择
this one
这个
They're really good at finding ways to avoid problems.
他们非常擅长寻找避免问题的方法。
You can always find a way to avoid problems.
你总能找到避免问题的方法。
And you did that...
而你却这么做了...
By manipulating everyone around him.
通过操纵他周围的每个人。
- You... - What?
- 你... - 什么？
You want to say that I am ungrateful and inhuman .
你想说我忘恩负义，没有人性。
And that's low, right?
这很低，对吧？
Jong Ye-ran, you are ungrateful.
钟艺兰，你忘恩负义。
They are more corrupt than beasts.
他们比禽兽还腐败。
How can you say that about yourself, my lord?
陛下，您怎么能这么说自己呢？
Even now, I'm still pretending like that.
直到现在，我还是那样假装。
About divorce...
关于离婚...
There is no way you will succeed.
你不可能成功。
government
政府
Looks like Master I will be very angry.
看来师父 我会很生气。
I've never seen it. He had never been this angry before.
我从来没有见过它。 他从来没有这么生气过。
I was careless.
我粗心。
I want to take action quickly.
我想尽快采取行动。
And did not take into account his dignity
并且没有考虑到他的尊严
I shouldn't have provoked him like this.
我不应该这样激怒他。
I think I may have provoked it. give him what he wants
我想可能是我挑衅的。 给他他想要的
I resist more than before
我比以前更抗拒
That means he didn't go out that night.
也就是说，他那天晚上没有出去。
But did you secretly hear what I said?
但你偷偷听到我说的话了吗？
So what should we do?
那么我们应该做什么呢？
are you okay.
你还好吗。
Let's go to the head garden tomorrow.
明天我们去头花园吧。
"Extra Scenes"
“额外场景”
What a waste.
真是浪费啊。
underfoot
脚下
Mistress's maids and guards
女主人的侍女和侍卫
Follow the lady downstairs and ask her.
跟着那位女士下楼询问她。
Let's go with that.
我们就这样吧。
Accept it.
接受。
a few more days
再过几天
Please tell the tailor to come see me.
请告诉裁缝来见我。
Accept it.
接受。